<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: English | Icemelon]]></title>
  <link href="http://ice-melon.github.io/blog/categories/english/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ice-melon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-29T01:13:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://ice-melon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[icemelon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[pick a random element from a long array]]></title>
    <link href="http://ice-melon.github.io/blog/2013/08/24/pick-a-random-element-from-a-long-array/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-24T22:53:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ice-melon.github.io/blog/2013/08/24/pick-a-random-element-from-a-long-array</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Suppose you have an array of n elemnets and you have to pick an element randomly. It is easy that you just pick each element with probability 1/n.</p>

<p>While if you don&rsquo;t know the size of the array, you receive the element one at a time. How to pick the element? In theory you could wait for all elements to come and compute the probility. But the stream may be too large to be stored in memory, which makes it infeasible. We want an algorithm that we do not have to store the elements and look at the elements twice.</p>

<p>Here comes the solution:</p>

<pre><code>1.Choose the first element with probability 1
2.Replace the first element with the second element, with probability 1/2
3.Replace the current element with the third element, with probability 1/3
4.Continue doing this until the stream ends.
</code></pre>

<p>Let&rsquo;s prove the correctness by induction:</p>

<pre><code>Suppose that after seeing n-1 elements, each of the first n-1 elements is chosen with equal probability.  
When you see the nth element, it is chosen with probability 1/n, and each of the other elements is chosen
with probability [1/(n-1)] * [(n-1) / n] = 1/n. 
Therefore all elements are chosen with equal probability.
</code></pre>

<p>The algorithm takes O(1) space and O(n) time, which is quite simple and beautiful.
For more information, see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reservoir_sampling">Reservior sample</a> on Wikipedia.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[People don’t buy what u do,they buy why U do]]></title>
    <link href="http://ice-melon.github.io/blog/2013/08/08/people-dont-buy-what-u-do-they-buy-why-u-do/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-08T23:03:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ice-melon.github.io/blog/2013/08/08/people-dont-buy-what-u-do-they-buy-why-u-do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several days ago, I waked up at 6 am and happened to watch a TED talk <a href="http://blog.ted.com/2010/05/04/how_great_leade/">&ldquo;How great leaders inspire action&rdquo;</a>. I was attracted by the speaker&rsquo;s terse idea and comfortable articulate  pronunciation.</p>

<p>The speaker,<a href="http://www.twitter.com/simonsinek">Simon Sinek</a>, is a brilliant marketing consultant and author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Start-Why-Leaders-Inspire-Everyone/dp/1591842808?tag=jasonwiener-20">Start of Why</a>. He believes  that all great organizations think, act, and communicate in the exact same way — and this is opposite of how most of us think, act, and communicate. He believes great companies and leaders communicate and inspire with a methodology he calls The Golden Circle.</p>

<p>Here is the example of Golden Circle.</p>

<blockquote><p>  If Apple were like everyone else their marketing message would be, “We make great computers. They are beautifully designed, simple to use, and user-friendly. Want to buy one?”</p>

<p>  However, this is how Apple actually communicates, “In everything we do we believe in challenging the status quo. We believe in thinking differently. The way we challenge the status quo is by making our products beautifully designed, simple to use, and user-friendly. We just happen to make great computers. Want to buy one?”</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://t1.baidu.com/it/u=1276415570,1783171753&amp;fm=21&amp;gp=0.jpg" title="Logo 1" alt="" /></p>

<p>Every person  knows <em>what</em> they do and some people know <em>how</em> to do it better, which may be service and skill. But only very few know <em>why</em> they do what they do. As the golden circle diagram showed, all great organizations
and people think inside out the diagram.</p>

<p>The goal is not to do business with people need what you have. The goal is to do business with people believe with what you believe. The first 2.5% of population are innovators; The next 13.5% people are early adopters.
The propagation law tells us if you want mass-market success or mass-market acceptance of  an idea, you can&rsquo;t have it until you achieve the tipping poin between 15% and 18%. Most of population just follow what others do.</p>

<p>When first generation of iphone came out, why so many people wait many hours to buy a iphone? Because these people believe what Apple believes. The innovators and early adoptors feel comfortable to make intuitive decisions that are driven by what their believe about the world and not just what product is available.</p>

<p>Recommend to watch the <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action.html">talk</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
